Miles Wu

milesswu.net
msw@milesswu.net
github.com/milesswu
linkedin.com/in/milesswu

EDUCATION _

University of California: Los Angeles | GPA: 3.86

- Bachelor of Science: Computer Science June 2022
- Dean's Honor List: Fall 2018, Winter 2019, Spring 2019, Spring 2020

EXPERIENCE

RISE, Co-founder & Internal Director

May 2020 - Sep 2020

- Organized an international community of 65 students and 70 industry mentors to
 provide an opportunity for students affected by the loss of summer jobs from COVID
 to receive support and structure similar to an internship experience.
- Recruited product managers, designers, and developers from **450+ applicants** to work in cross-functional teams to ideate, design, and develop <u>original products</u>.
- Directed teams' focus towards a structured sprint-based Agile workflow with an
 emphasis on user feedback based feature prioritization, resulting in all 7 teams
 successfully launching their MVPs in just 9 weeks.
- Acted as a subject matter expert for PMs and developers by preparing documentation/workshops on product pitches, user interviews, team management, and using technologies like Github and Firebase.

UCLA ACM Hack, Hackschool Director

Nov 2019 - Present

- Taught workshops and structured curriculum for quarter long web development educational programs with average turnout of 70+ participants per week and 200+ views per session; the highest of any ACM committee.
- Directed <u>Bloom</u>, an intro to web dev and design fellowship with **over 465 members** created for aspiring developers and designers to learn and apply fundamental skills.
- Took initiative in suggesting and implementing a partnership/group system for fellows to develop relationships in the online environment, dramatically increasing interaction and engagement.

Society of Women Engineers, FullStack Developer

Nov 2019 - Present

- Building an Event Portal in preparation for SWE's largest annual event, Evening with Industry, based on the Board members' specifications.
- Responsible for handling user registration; creating signup pages with **React** and working with endpoints on our **Node Express** server.

PROJECTS_

Story Seeker, Amazon Alexa Skills Challenge

Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

- Spearheaded an end-to-end product centering around an Alexa Skill which allows users to purchase and interact with choice-based stories.
- Used React & Redux to implement the front-end architecture for a web platform where authors can write and maintain their stories using an interactive graph-based user interface consisting of nodes and branches.
- Handled **data serialization** of author built stories, translating graph structure into a JSON format that could easily be processed by Alexa.
- Won "Best in Show" at UCLA ACM's Annual Tech Gala.

Water Wars, LA Hacks

Mar 2019

- Created a web app with React to gamify and promote water conservation.
- Utilized **Google Maps' Geocoding API** to respond to user searches for addresses and display the water usage of buildings in those areas.

SUMMARY

Passionate about peer-to-peer support, collaborative learning, and realizing solutions that create user delight.

Using leadership experiences and technical capabilities to drive innovation and impact; making a difference and adding value to peers, users, and clients.

SKILLS

Programming Languages



Frameworks/Tools



Leadership

User Driven Problem Solving

Overseeing Developer Workflow

Facilitating Productive Discussion

Teaching Communication